

Patricia McPhee

TECHNICAL WRITER
CONTENT DEVELOPER
UX WRITER

Broomfield, CO 303-835-4906 hi@patriciamcphee.com patriciamcphee.github.io/aboutme/

About Me

I have 25 years of experience creating scenario and goal-based content to help IT professionals achieve more with technology. I'm passionate about bringing stale or unusable content back to life by taking the guesswork out of complex technical content.

Education

10/2010 - 05/2012 **Kaplan University** BS in Health Science

02/1999 - 04/2001 DeVry University - Denver

AS Computer Systems (networking and telecommunications)

Work Experience

05/2020 - Pres.

Content Developer, Contractor Microsoft/Kforce

Work collaboratively with the Azure VMware Solution core engineering and UX Research teams to develop scenario and goal-based content. Write and edit UX microcopy and UI strings. Conduct content audits of existing content to identify areas for improvement. Use qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2019 - 06/2021

Freelance

- Extreme Networks (2020 2021) Reviewed and edited network hardware content for the FIPS program.
- Netdata (2020) Wrote product content for a Linux server performance tool.
- ZPE Systems (2019-2020) Wrote a marketing campaign eBook. Wrote video scripts, provided the voiceover, and produced how-to videos.
- Wax.io (2019) Contributed to blockchain blog articles.

03/2019 - 06/2019 Technical Writer II

LivePerson

Wrote SDK and API guides for mobile messaging app.

01/2018 - 01/2019 **Technical Writer II** Microsoft

Worked collaboratively with the Microsoft Edge and Windows networking core teams. Wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings. Conducted content audits to identify areas for potential improvement. Used qualitative and quantitative data to make data-driven decisions.

07/2017 - 12/2017

Technical Writer. Contractor

Oculus/Facebook

Developed internal cross-functional workflows and process documentation for a virtual reality R&D environment.

08/2016 - 05/2017 Software Technical Writer

GE Healthcare

Worked collaboratively with customers and support to update the outdated installation and upgrade guides. The rework resulted in more successful upgrades and reduced customer support calls.



Skills

Technical Writing

Content Strategy

UX/UI Writing

Information Architecture

Project Management

Instructional Design

DITA/oXygen

Markdown

Git/GitHub

Agile/Jira/Azure DevOps

Adobe InDesign

Adobe Premiere Pro

Video Production

Figma/Adobe UX

Jekyll (static site generator)

Work Experience (cont'd)

09/2015 - 07/2016

Technical Writer II

Amazon

Wrote internal feature announcements and task-oriented procedure guides for warehouse employees.

03/2015 - 09/2015

Technical Writer, Contractor

Charter Communications

Worked collaboratively with video-on-demand and networking engineers to write standard procedures. Wrote Python scripts for system administration tasks.

01/2014 - 10/2014

Technical Writer

SolidFire, a NetApp company

Wrote release notes, configuration and troubleshooting guides, white papers, and solution briefs for the cloud storage solution. Also, wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings.

12/2012 - 12/2013

Technical Writer, Contractor

Sybase/SAP

Wrote installation, configuration, and API guides for a mobile money app.

07/2012 - 01/2013

Technical Writer, Contractor

CarpeDatum

Wrote design specifications and instructor-led training guides for enterprise planning and budgeting software. Also, wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings.

08/2011 - 07/2012

Technical Writer, Contractor

Level 3 Communications, a CenturyLink company

Wrote fiber optic provisioning procedures for field technicians. Also, wrote and edited UX microcopy and UI strings.

Achievements

- · Wrote shell scripts to automate API content publishing.
- Co-authored Excel 2010 in Simple Steps. ISBN: 0-27-373613-2